Eugene Otto Weber Murman Watercolors of California Flora, 1941-1961
Louise M. Darling Biomedical Library History and Special Collections Division
- Cupressaceae (Cypress) Family. 1942-1961, Series 27.; 17 entries
  - Juniperus californica (California juniper).1/20/59 (Box 17, Folder 329)
    Hwy. #78 between Banner and Scissors crossing
  - Juniperus californica var. utahensis (California juniper).10/7/42 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    also slide #168; Cedar Flat, Inyo National Forest
  - Juniperus communis var. montana (dwarf juniper).10/30/42 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    also slide #169; Shasta National Forest, section 21, T.39 north, R.6 west, M.D.M., 6,200' elevation
  - Juniperus osteosperma (Utah juniper).1/10/61 (Box 26, Folder 512)
    Mono County; Bryce Canyon, UT
  - Libocedrus decurrens (incense cedar). (Box 12, Folder 230)
    also slide #198; no collection date; Yosemite National Park; plate indicates Family: Pinaceae
  - Thuja plicata (canoe cedar).4/15/43 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    also slide #170; Oregon
- Dipsacaceae (Teasel) Family. 1951, Series 28.; 1 entry
  - Dipsacus fullonum (teasel).8/27/51 (Box 4, Folder 69)
- Droseraceae (Sundew) Family., Series 29.; 1 entry
  - Drosera rotundifolia (roundleaved sundew). (Box 4, Folder 70)
    no collection date; marshy spots in the Sierra Nevada from Tulare to Siskiyou Counties, and south, near the coast, to Mendocino County (fr. Jepson)
- Elaeagnaceae (Oleaster [Loaster]) Family. 1958-1960, Series 30.; 1 entry
  - Shepherdia argentea (buffalo-berry).3/15/60, 1/6/58, 9/28/60 (Box 23, Folder 443)
    Cuyama River bed, Ozena, Santa Barbara County at 3,000'; Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden
- Ephedraceae (Mormon-tea) Family. 1957, Series 31.; 1 entry
  - Ephedra californica (California ephedra; desert tea).5/31/57 (Box 22, Folder 433)
    Twentynine Palms, San Bernardino County; plate indicates Family: Gnetaceae
- Ericaceae (Heath) Family. 1941-1957, Series 32.; 17 entries
  one entry has been moved to Family: Monotropaceae, according to IPNI classification
  - Arbutus menziesii (madrone).1/4/54, 4/20/54 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    Redding, Shasta County
  - Arctostaphylos canescens (hoary manzanita).3/7/57, 6/13/57 (Box 25, Folder 492)
  - Arctostaphylos glauca (bigberry manzanita).1/2/52, 7/11/54 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Arctostaphylos hookeri (Hooker's manzanita)3/7/57, 6/13/57 (Box 25, Folder 493)
  - Arctostaphylos insularis (island manzanita).6/11/55, 9/4/57 (Box 25, Folder 491)
  - Arctostaphylos morroensis (Morro manzanita).3/26/55, 6/13/57 (Box 25, Folder 490)
  - Cassiope mertensiana (western mountain heather).7/16/57 (Box 25, Folder 485)
    north slope, Echo Ridge, Yosemite National Park, 10,000' elevation
  - Comarostaphylis diversifolia (summer holly; mock arbute).6/3/57, 9/57 (Box 25, Folder 489)
  - Gaultheria shallon (salal).6/9/41 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    Trinidad, Humboldt County
  - Kalmia polifolia (American laurel).7/15/57 (Box 25, Folder 487)
  - Ladum glandulosum (western labrador tea).7/15/57 (Box 25, Folder 488)
  - Phyllodoce breweri (red heather).7/15/57 (Box 25, Folder 486)
  - Pirola aphylla (leafless shin-leaf).6/13/41 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    Patrick Creek, Del Norte County
  - Pterospora andromeda (pine drops). (Box 4, Folder 75)
    rich humus beneath pines, 4,000'-7,500' elevation; common, San Jacinto, San Bernardino, and San Gabriel mountains; Sierra Nevada, etc.; a saprophyte (fr. Jepson)
  - Rhododendron californicum (California rose bay).6/8/41 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Rhododendron occidentale (western azalea).6/8/41 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - A saprophyte. (Box 4, Folder 78)
    Sierra Nevada, North Coast ranges, north to Washington; montane, under pines or firs, 6,000'-8,000' elevation; infrequent (fr. Jepson); no other data
- Euphorbiaceae (Spurge) Family. 1957-1959, Series 33.; 3 entries
  - Acalypha californica (California copperleaf).1/6/59 (Box 17, Folder 339)
  - Croton californicus (California or desert croton; el barbasco).5/31/57 (Box 22, Folder 431)
  - Tetracoccus didicus (San Diego tetracoccus).1/6/59 (Box 17, Folder 330)
- Fabaceae [Leguminosae] (Pea) Family. 1941-1961, Series 34.; 29 entries
  - Acacia farnesiana (sweet acacia; huisache).2/7/53 (Box 7, Folder 127)
    also slide #190; San Diego County
  - Acacia greggii (cat's claw; una de gato).7/11/54 (Box 7, Folder 126)
  - Amorpha californica (false indigo).6/30/61 (Box 19, Folder 377)
    Big Pine Mt., Santa Barbara County, 6,500' elevation
  - Astragalus menziesii (Menzies' rattle-weed; gray loco).8/22/51 (Box 7, Folder 128)
    Pismo Beach, San Luis Obispo County
  - Calliandra eriophylla (calliandra).7/11/54 (Box 7, Folder 129)
    east Imperial County
  - Cassia armata (desert cassia).5/13/54 (Box 7, Folder 130)
  - Cercidium floridum (palo verde).7/15/54, 9/15/54 (Box 7, Folder 131)
  - Cercidium microphyllum (palo verde).6/6/61 (Box 26, Folder 501)
    Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden, Claremont
  - Cercis occidentalis (western red-bud).4/3/54 (Box 7, Folder 132)
  - Dalea californica (California dalea).5/31/57 (Box 22, Folder 434)
  - Dalea emoryi (white dalea).1/19/59 (Box 17, Folder 333)
    Palm Springs, Riverside County
  - Dalea schottii (Schott's dalea).5/17/58 (Box 18, Folder 347)
    Coachella Valley, Riverside County
  - Hoffmanseggia microphylla (small-leaved hoffmanseggia).4/22/61 (Box 26, Folder 502)
  - Lupinus albifrons (silver lupine).4/11/59 (Box 17, Folder 334)
    Cuyama Valley near Venticopa, Santa Barbara County
  - Lupinus arboreus (tree lupine; yellow bush lupine).8/22/51 (Box 7, Folder 133)
  - Lupinus excubitus var. johnstonii (Inyo lupine).6/3/52 (Box 7, Folder 134)
    Angeles Crest, Los Angeles County, 6,000' elevation
  - Lupinus hirsutissimus (lupine).3/23/41 (Box 7, Folder 135)
    Tujunga Canyon
  - Lupinus longifolius (Pauma lupine).2/3/59 (Box 17, Folder 335)
  - Lupinus nanus (blue-and-white lupine).5/10/42 (Box 7, Folder 136)
    Los Angeles County
  - Lupinus stiversi (Stivers lupine).6/1/42 (Box 7, Folder 137)
  - Lupinus succulentus (lupine).3/23/41 (Box 7, Folder 138)
    Tujunga Canyon, Los Angeles County
  - Olneya tesota (ironwood; palo de hierro).5/4/59, 7/17/59 (Box 17, Folder 336)
  - Olneya tesota (ironwood; palo de hierro).7/1/57, photograph by Dalton E. Merkel (Box 17, Folder 337)
    Yaqui Well, Anza Borrego Desert State Park, San Diego County
  - Parosela spinosa (smoke tree).6/15/57, photograph by Dalton E. Merkel (Box 22, Folder 435)
    San Felipe Wash, San Diego County
  - Parosela spinosa (smoke tree).5/31/57 (Box 22, Folder 436)
  - Pickeringia montana (chaparral pea).5/26/55 (Box 24, Folder 473)
  - Prosopis juliflora (mesquite).5/13/54 (Box 7, Folder 139)
  - Prosopis pubescens (screwbean; tornilla).5/13/54 (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - Vicia californica (California vetch).5/26/55 (Box 24, Folder 474)
- Fagaceae (Beech) Family. 1952-1954, Series 35.; 26 entries
  - Castanopsis chrysophylla (giant chinquapin).8/20/53 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    also slide #171; Cavce Juntion, Oregon
  - Castanopsis sempervirens (bush chinquapin).8/10/53 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    also slide #172; Madera County, 7,000' elevation
  - Lithocarpus densiflora (tan oak).7 /23/53 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    also slide #173; also a Christmas card; Big Sur, Monterey County
  - Lithocarpus densiflora (tan oak).6/23/53 (Box 5, Folder 83a)
    also a Christmas card; Big Sur, Monterey County
  - Quecus agrifolia (coast life oak).2/23/52, 3/25/52 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    also slide #174; also a Christmas card; Encino, Verdugo Hills, Los Angeles County; Ojai, Ventura County; Mulholland Drive, Los Angeles County
  - Quercus agrifolia (coast live oak).3/29/52 (Box 5, Folder 84a)
    also a Christmas card; Mulholland Drive, Los Angeles County
  - Quercus agrifolia; Quercus kelloggii; Quercus wislizenii; Quercus morehus (black oaks)., photographs of bark (Box 4, Folder 80)
    Jackson Lake, 6,000' elevation; Verdugo Hills; Fresno County; Los Angeles County; no collection dates
  - Quercus chrysolepis (canyon oak; maul oak).6/3/52, 9/15/52 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    also slide #175; Angeles Crest, Los Angeles County, 6,000' elevation
  - Quercus chrysolepis; Quercus douglasii; Quercus engelmannii; Quercus lobata (white oaks)., photographs of bark (Box 5, Folder 100)
    Angeles Crest, Oak Flat Public Camp, San Marino, Encino, Los Angeles County; no collection date
  - Quercus douglasii (blue oak; roble).4/19/52, 9/3/52 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    also slide #187; Oak Flat Public Camp, Los Angeles County, 2,100' elevation
  - Quercus douglasii (blue oak).9/1/52, photograph by Rosaleen M. Murman (Box 19, Folder 364)
    Oak Flat, Los Angeles County, 2,100' elevation
  - Quercus dumosa (scrub oak; chaparro).4/19/52, 9/20/52 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    also slide #176; Whitaker Summit, Los Angeles County, 2,950' elevation; Mulholland Drive, Los Angeles County
  - Quercus durata (leather oak).5/17/53, 10/25/53 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    also slide #177; near Happy Canyon Camp Ground; Cachuma Camp Ground; San Rafael Mountains, San Bernardino County
  - Quercus engelmannii (mesa oak).4/20/52, 9/15/52 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    also slide #178; Pasadena, Los Angeles County; Palomar, San Diego County, 3,800' elevation
  - Quercus garryana (Oregon oak; Garry oak).5/4/53, 9/15/53 (Box 5, Folder 90)
    also slide #179; Willamette, Rogue River Valley, Oregon
  - Quercus kellogii (California black oak).4/30/52, 9/4/52 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    also slide #180; Santa Isabel, San Diego County, 3,200' elevation; Jackson Lake, Los Angeles County, 6,000' elevation
  - Quercus lobata (valley oak; roble)3/29/52, 9/3/52, 9/6/52 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    also slide #181; Calabasas, Los Angeles County; Oak Flat Public Camp, Los Angeles County, 2,100' elevation
  - Quercus morehus (oracle oak).4/22/52, 9/12/52 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    also slide #182; Sonora, Tuolumne County, 2,000' elevation
  - Quercus palmeri (Palmer oak).5/14/54, 9/9/54 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    also a Christmas card; Boulevard, San Diego County
  - Quercus palmeri (Palmer oak).5/14/54 (Box 5, Folder 94a)
  - Quercus palmeri (Palmer oak).9/9/54, photograph and a map (Box 5, Folder 95)
    Boulevard, San Diego County
  - Quercus sadleriana (deer oak; Sadler oak).7/8/53, 9/11/53 (Box 5, Folder 96)
    also slide #183; Cafe Junction, Siskiyou Mountains, Oregon
  - Quercus tomentella (island oak).5/21/52, 11/1/52 (Box 5, Folder 97)
    also slide #184; Santa Barbara Botanic Garden
  - Quercus turbinella subsp. californica (turbinella oak).4/11/54, 9/30/54 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    Mint Canyon, Los Angeles County; Joshua Tree National Monument
  - Quercus vaccinifolia (huckleberry oak).7/1/52, 8/1/52 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    also slide #185; Camp Tamarack, Calaveras County, 6,700' elevation
  - Quercus wislizenii; Quercus wislizenii var. frutescens (interior live oak).5/10/52, 9/10/52, 9/13/52 (Box 6, Folder 101)
    also slide #186; Isabella, Kern County; Angeles Crest, Los Angeles County, 6,000' elevation
- Fouquieriaceae (Ocotillo [Candlewood]) Family. 1941, Series 36.; 2 entries
  - Fouquieria splendens (candlewood; ocotillo).3/30/41, photograph (Box 6, Folder 102)
    Colorado Desert, Borrego Valley, San Diego County
  - Fouquieria splendens (coach-whip; ocotillo).3/30/41 (Box 6, Folder 103)
- Fumariaceae (Fumitory) Family. 1957, Series 37.
  two entries have been moved to Family: Papaveraceae, according to IPNI classification
- Garryaceae (Silk Tassel) Family. 1953-1957, Series 38.; 2 entries
  - Garrya elliptica (silk tassel bush).2/21/53, 6/15/53 (Box 6, Folder 104)
    Big Sur, Monterey County
  - Garrya flavescens var. pallida (bacigalupi; ashi silktassel).3/7/57 (Box 22, Folder 424)
- Gnetaceae (Gnetum) Family. 1957, Series 39.
  entry has been moved to Family: Ephedraceae, according to IPNI classification
    one entry has been moved to Family: Ephedraceae, according to IPNI classification
- Grossulariaceae (Currant) Family. 1958, Series 40.; 1 entry
  - Ribes viburnifolium (Catalina currant).2/3/58 (Box 18, Folder 352)
    Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden; plate indicates Family: Saxifragaceae
- Hippocastanaceae (Horse-chestnut) Family. 1955, Series 41.; 1 entry
  - Aesculus californica (buckeye).5/21/55 (Box 21, Folder 408)
    Knight' Ferry, Stanislaus County; plate shows Family as Sapindaceae (Buckeye Family)
- Hydrophyllaceae (Waterleaf [Phacelia]) Family. 1942-1952, Series 42.; 7 entries
  - Eriodictyon crassifolium (yerba santa; mountain bush).6/3/52 (Box 6, Folder 105)
  - Nemophila maculata (spotted nemophila; five-spot).5/5/42 (Box 6, Folder 106)
    Kern County
  - Nemophila menziesii (baby blue-eyes).5/1/42 (Box 6, Folder 107)
  - Phacelia campanularia (California blue-bell).5/8/42 (Box 6, Folder 108)
  - Phacelia parryi (Parry's Canterbury bell).5/15/42 (Box 6, Folder 109)
  - Phacelia viscida (sticky blue-bell).5/20/42 (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Phacelia whitlavia (California blue-bell). (Box 6, Folder 111)
    Glendale, Los Angeles County; no collection date
- Iridaceae (Iris) Family. 1941, Series 43.; 2 entries
  - Iris douglasiana (mountain iris).6/11/41 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    Smith River, Del Norte County
  - Iris hartwegii (Sierra iris).6/3/41 (Box 6, Folder 113)
    Loch Lomond, Lake County
- Juglandaceae (Walnut )Family. 1956, Series 44.; 1 entry
  - Juglans californica (So. California black walnut).3/18/56, 8/21/56 (Box 19, Folder 374)
    Woodland Hills, Los Angeles County
- Krameriaceae (Krameria) Family. 1958, Series 45.; 1 entry
  - Krameria grayi (Gray krameria; white ratany).5/17/58 (Box 18, Folder 344)
- Lamiaceae [Labiatae] (Mint) Family. 1941-1959, Series 46.; 16 entries
  - Hyptis emoryi (bee sage; desert lavender).1/20/59 (Box 17, Folder 332)
  - Mentha pulegium (pennyroyal; poleo).8/26/51 (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Monardella lanceolata (mustang mint).6/30/42 (Box 6, Folder 115)
    Santa Monica Mountains, Los Angeles County
  - Monardella linoides var. stricta (no common name).6/11/55 (Box 24, Folder 472)
  - Salazaria mexicana (bladder sage).3/20/58, 4/17/58 (Box 18, Folder 345)
  - Salazaria mexicana (bladder sage).5/17/58, color photograph by Rosaleen M. Murman (Box 18, Folder 346)
  - Salvia carduacea (thistle sage).5/1/41 (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - Salvia carnosa (blue sage). (Box 6, Folder 117)
    San Bernardino Mountains; Mojave Desert, Inyo and Siskiyou Counties; north to WA; found on arid mountain slopes & plains; 2,500'-7,500' (fr. Jepson)
  - Salvia clevelandi (sage).8/31/51 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    San Diego County
  - Salvia columbariae (chia).5/10/42 (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - Salvia leucophylla (purple sage).5/14/43 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    Chatsworth Hills, Los Angeles County
  - Salvia spathacea (crimson sage; hummingbird sage).6/28/53 (Box 7, Folder 121)
  - Scutellaria angustifolia (scull cap).7/16/41 (Box 7, Folder 122)
    Chilao, Angeles National Forest
  - Sphacele calycina (pitcher sage).6/28/53 (Box 21, Folder 420)
  - Trichostema lanatum (romero).4/19/41 (Box 7, Folder 123)
    also slide #188; Rancho Santa Ana, Orange County
  - Trichostema lanceolatum (vinegar weed; camphor weed).8/30/51 (Box 7, Folder 124)
- Lauraceae (Laurel) Family. 1952, Series 47.; 1 entry
  - Umbellularia californica (California laurel).2/18/52, 10/1/52 (Box 7, Folder 125)
    also slide #189; Verdugo Hills, Los Angeles County
- Lennoaceae (Lennoa) Family. 1954, Series 48.; 3 entries
  - Ammobroma sonorae (sand food; biatatk)4/24/54 (Box 8, Folder 141)
    Sand hills west of Yuma, Imperial County
  - Ammobroma sonorae (sand food; biatatk).4/25/54 (Box 8, Folder 142)
    sand hills west of Yuma, Imperial County
  - Pholisma arenarium (scaly-stemmed sand plant).5/25/54 (Box 8, Folder 143)
- Lentibulariaceae (Bladderwort )Family. 1950, Series 49.; 2 entries
  - Pinguicula vulgaris (common butterwort).5/19/50 (Box 23, Folder 454)
    French Flat 2 mi. south of Gasquet, Del Norte County
  - Utricularia vulgaris (common bladderwort). (Box 8, Folder 144)
    no collection date; widely distributed in Calif. but rather infrequent; Bear Valley, San Bernardino Mts.; Kern River; Bouldin Island, Olema; Santa Rosa;...
- Liliaceae (Lily) Family. 1941-1960, Series 50.; 52 entries
  four entries have been moved to Family: Trilliaceae and seven entries to Family: Agavaceae, according to IPNI classification
    four entries have been moved to Family: Trilliacea, according to IPNI classification, and seven entries have been moved to Family: Agavaceae
  - Brodiaea bridgesii (Bridges' brodiaea).6/10/42 (Box 8, Folder 145)
    Butte County
  - Brodiaea capitata (blue dicks).3/20/42 (Box 8, Folder 146)
  - Brodiaea coronaria (harvest brodiaea).6/15/41 (Box 8, Folder 147)
    Darlington, Del Norte County
  - Brodiaea hyacinthina (white brodiaea).6/10/42 (Box 8, Folder 148)
    near Ukiah, Mendocino County
  - Brodiaea ida-maia (firecracker plant).6/4/41 (Box 8, Folder 149)
    Cummings, Mendocino County
  - Brodiaea ixioides (golden brodiaea).6/10/42 (Box 8, Folder 150)
  - Brodiaea laxa (grass nut; Ithuriel's spear).6/4/41 (Box 8, Folder 151)
  - Brodiaea pulchella (ookow).6/4/41 (Box 8, Folder 152)
    Mendocino County
  - Brodiaea stellaris (star-flowered brodiaea).6/12/42 (Box 8, Folder 153)
    Humboldt County
  - Brodiaea volubilis (twining brodiaea).6/10/42 (Box 8, Folder 154)
  - Calochortus albus (white fairy lantern).6/24/42 (Box 8, Folder 155)
  - Calochortus amabilis (golden fairy lantern).6/24/42 (Box 8, Folder 156)
  - Calochortus catalinae (Catalina mariposa).3/24/42 (Box 8, Folder 157)
  - Calochortus clavatus (yellow mariposa). (Box 8, Folder 158)
    no collection date; Los Angeles County
  - Calochortus kennedyi (desert mariposa). (Box 8, Folder 159)
    no collection date; frequently found in hard clay or gravely soil; Mojave Desert west to Ventury County, north to southern Nevada and Arizona; in May (fr. Jepson)
  - Calochortus luteus var. oculatus (yellow mariposa).6/14/42 (Box 8, Folder 160)
  - Calochortus luteus var. vestae (mariposa lily).6/4/41 (Box 9, Folder 161)
    Tan Oak Park, Mendocino County
  - Calochortus maweanus major (hairy star tulip).6/10/42 (Box 9, Folder 162)
  - Calochortus monophyllus (yellow star tulip).6/10/42 (Box 9, Folder 163)
  - Calochortus monophyllus var. wallacei (yellow star tulip; cat's ear).6/10/42 (Box 9, Folder 164)
  - Calochortus plummerae (Plummer's mariposa).6/27/43 (Box 9, Folder 165)
  - Calochortus uniflorus (large-flowered star tulip).6/10/42 (Box 9, Folder 166)
  - Calochortus venustus eldorado (lovely mariposa).6/24/42 (Box 9, Folder 167)
    Tuolumne County
  - Calochortus venustus eldorado var. purp. (lovely mariposa).6/24/42 (Box 9, Folder 168)
  - Camassia leichtlinii (blue form Leichtlin's camass).4/29/42 (Box 9, Folder 169)
    Northern Coast Range, CA; type specimen from Winchester, OR
  - Camassia leichtlinii (white form Leichtlin's camass).4/30/42 (Box 9, Folder 170)
  - Chlorogalum pomeridianum (amole).5/14/43 (Box 9, Folder 171)
  - Erythronium californicum (California fawn lily).4/15/42 (Box 9, Folder 172)
  - Erythronium hartwegii (Sierra fawn lily).4/18/42 (Box 9, Folder 173)
    Butte County foothills
  - Erythronium hendersonii (Henderson's fawn lily).4/13/42 (Box 9, Folder 174)
    Siskiyou County; type specimen from Josephine County, OR
  - Erythronium revolutum (coast fawn lily).4/16/42 (Box 9, Folder 175)
    Navarro River 15 mi. inland, Mendocino County
  - Fritillaria lanceolata (checker lily; mission bells).4/29/42 (Box 9, Folder 176)
  - Fritillaria pluriflora (adobe lily).3/24/43 (Box 9, Folder 177)
  - Fritillaria pudica (yellow fritillary).4/29/42 (Box 9, Folder 178)
    Sierra County to Siskiyou County; type specimen from southwest Idaho
  - Fritillaria recurva (scarlet fritillary).4/10/43 (Box 9, Folder 179)
  - Fritillaria recurva (scarlet fritillary).4/24/43 (Box 9, Folder 180)
  - Hesperocallis undulata (desert lily).3/1/41 (Box 10, Folder 181)
  - Lilium bolanderi (no common name).6/13/41 (Box 10, Folder 182)
    Patricks Creek, Siskiyou County
  - Lilium columbianum (Oregon lily).6/8/41 (Box 10, Folder 183)
  - Lilium humboldtii (Humboldt's lily).7/3/41 (Box 10, Folder 184)
    Santa Anita Canyon
  - Lilium kellogii (Kellog's lily).6/13/41 (Box 10, Folder 185)
  - Lilium kellogii (Kellog's lily).6/24/42 (Box 10, Folder 186)
  - Lilium maritimum (coast lily).7/11/42 (Box 10, Folder 187)
  - Lilium occidentale (Eureka lily).8/25/42 (Box 10, Folder 188)
    near coast, Humboldt & Del Norte Counties; type specimen from Brookings, OR
  - Lilium pardalinum (leopard lily).7/9/42 (Box 10, Folder 189)
    Medocino County
  - Lilium pardalinum var. minor (Shasta leopard lily).7/2/42 (Box 10, Folder 190)
  - Lilium parryi (lemon lily).7/7/42 (Box 10, Folder 192)
    San Bernardino County
  - Lilium parryi (lemon lily).7/1/42, (1959) (Box 10, Folder 192a)
    San Bernardino Mtns.; this painting is dated 1959
  - Lilium parvum (small tiger lily).6/24/42 (Box 10, Folder 191)
    Placer County
  - Lilium rubescens (chaparral lily).7/2/42 (Box 10, Folder 193)
  - Nolina Parryi (Parry nolina).5/18/58, photograph by Rosaleen M. Murman (Box 20, Folder 383)
    Pioneer Town, Morongo Valley, San Bernardino County
  - Nolina Parryi (Parry nolina).5/18/58, 4/21/60 (Box 23, Folder 452)
- Loasaceae (Loasa) Family. 1961, Series 51.; 2 entries
  - Mentzelia lindleyi (blazing star). (Box 11, Folder 203)
    no collection date; Mt. Hamilton Range; Sierra Nevada foothills from Tuolumne to Tulare Counties; rocky canyon slopes, 500'-2,000' (fr. Jepson)
  - Petalonyx thurberi (sandpaper plant).4/22/61 (Box 26, Folder 504)
- Loranthaceae (Mistletoe) Family., Series 52.
  three entries have been moved to Family: Viscaceae, according to IPNI classification
- Malvaceae (Mallow) Family. 1951-1961, Series 53.; 2 entries
  - Sphaeralcea ambigua (apricot mallow).8/3/51 (Box 11, Folder 205)
  - Sphaeralcea emoryi (Emory's mallow).7/30/61 (Box 26, Folder 506)
- Monotropaceae (Indian Pipe) Family., Series 54.; 1 entry
  - Sarcodes sanguinea (snowplant). (Box 4, Folder 79)
    pinewoods, 4,000'-8,000' elevation; common, Trinity and Siskyou Counties; a saprophyte (fr. Jepson); plate indicates Family: Ericaceae
- Myricaceae (Bayberry [Sweet-gale]) Family. 1954, Series 55.; 1 entry
  - Myrica californica (wax myrtle).4/3/54, 7/11/54 (Box 11, Folder 206)
- Nyctaginaceae (Four-o'clock) Family., Series 56.; 1 entry
  - Abronia umbellata (common sand-verbena). (Box 11, Folder 207)
    no collection date; common along seashore from Los Angeles County to San Francisco and Eureka, north to Washington (fr. Jepson)
- Oleaceae (Olive [Ash]) Family. 1955, Series 57.; 4 entries
  - Fraxinus anomala (dwarf ash; single-leaf ash).8/27/55 (Box 24, Folder 475)
    Providence and Panamint Mountains; type specimen from Leeds, UT
  - Fraxinus dipetala (foothill ash).3/19/55, 6/11/55 (Box 24, Folder 478)
  - Fraxinus oregona (Oregon ash).7/6/55 (Box 24, Folder 476)
    throughout cismontane California; type specimen from Salem, OR
  - Fraxinus velutina (velvet ash).3/19/55, 6/11/55 (Box 24, Folder 477)
- Onagraceae (Evening Primrose) Family. 1941-1961, Series 58.; 8 entries
  - Clarkia elegans (no common name).6/1/43 (Box 11, Folder 208)
    also slide #191; Los Angeles County
  - Epilobium angustifolium (fire weed).6/11/41 (Box 11, Folder 209)
  - Godetia grandiflora (large flowered godetia).6/10/42 (Box 11, Folder 210)
  - Godetia viminea (orchid-flowered godetia).6/20/42 (Box 11, Folder 211)
  - Oenothera californica (evening primrose).6/2/42 (Box 11, Folder 212)
    near Gorman, Los Angeles County
  - Oenothera cardiophylla var. splendens (heart-leaved primrose).4/22/61 (Box 26, Folder 509)
  - Oenothera hookerii (evening primrose).6/14/42 (Box 11, Folder 213)
  - Zauschneria californica (Mexican balsamea). (Box 11, Folder 214)
    no collection date; cost ranges from Mendocino and Lake Counties to coastal So. California; dry benches, rocky hillsides or cliffs, 50'-4,000' (fr. Jepson)
- Orchidaceae (Orchid) Family. 1941-1942, Series 59.; 6 entries